Cody Yuill

313 Jasper cres, Rockland, Ontario, K4K 0B9 Phone: (613)222-2982 | Email: codyyuill@hotmail.com

LinkedIn:linkedin.com/in/CodyYuill Portfolio: codyyuill.github.io/Portfolio/

Github: github.com/CodyYuill

Full stack web developer using knowledge of game development to create mobile first environments largely focused on UI/UX. Recently earned a certificate in full stack development from Carleton University, developing skills in Javascript, CSS, API's, Database's and responsive web design. With each new project strives to write clean understandable code while focusing on creating a good UX. Looks forward to applying their skills to a quality-driven team to create engaging and memorable experiences on the web.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: JavaScript ES6+, CSS3, HTML5, SQL

Applications: GitHub, Heroku, MySQL Workbench, Mongo Atlas, Microsoft Office

Tools: JQuery, Node.js, MongoDB, Mongoose, Express, Sequelize, Bootstrap(and like tools)

PROJECTS

Vibe Cannon | github.com/CodyYuill/Vibe-Cannon | codyyuill.github.io/Vibe-Cannon/

- Summary: Search a song by title and artist and receive various information from multiple sources
- Role: Logic
- Tools: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bulma, YouTube API, Vimeo API, Rebrand.ly, iTunes API, Lyrics.OVH, jQuery

Weather Dashboard | <u>github.com/CodyYuill/WeatherDashboard</u> | <u>codyyuill.github.io/WeatherDashboard/</u>

- Summary: Weather dashboard that provides current and 5 day weather forecasts in cities
- Role: Sole author
- Tools: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, OpenWeather API, Bootstrap, Luxon

The Games Folder | github.com/CodyYuill/The-Games-Folder | group1-project2.herokuapp.com/

- Summary: Buy and review video games online.
- Role: Backend
- Tools: Javascript, CSS, HTML, Bootstrap, MySQL, Express, Heroku, Node.js, Handlebars, JSON Web Tokens

EXPERIENCE

Flightless Bees Student Dev Team

2019-2020

Game Programmer

Ottawa, ON

Developed and designed a video game in an agile environment with a group of 10 students Key Accomplishments:

- Designed and developed two different enemies with their own Al
- Implemented all character animations
- Aided programmer lead in QA testing

McDonalds 2017-2020 Team leader Kanata, ON

Served customers from all areas of the world in a high-paced, high-energy fast-food environment

Key Accomplishments:

- Satisfied an average of four-hundred guests a day
- Coordinated with all areas of the restaurant to ensure correct food and drink deliveries in a timely fashion
- Promoted to crew trainer after 8 months
- Promoted to team leader 10 months after crew trainer promotion
- Trained new crew members on all company policies and procedures, ensuring daily expectations were met and customers were treated properly

EDUCATION

Certificate, Full Stack Web Development – Carleton University

Nov 2020 - May 2021

Ottawa, ON

Advanced Diploma, Game Development – Algonquin College

2017-2020

Ottawa, ON